Guide to the Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute AD.RG.024.1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Promotional and Program Materials
2007-2020
2008-2015
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.024.1
7 Linear Feet in 2 legal size document boxes; 1 OS Flat File; 3 [16x20] OS boxes of 343 DVDs; 157 USB flash drives
157 Items [individual USB drives]
197 Megabytes of digital publications stored in the CDS-ASC repository
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007 through 2020, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade is relevant to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public.
Scope and Contents
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007 through 2020, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade will be of interest to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public.
Materials include printed calendars; promotional cards, flyers, and brochures; a small collection of printed photographic materials; published "Year in Review" yearbooks; and audiovisual files (photos, videos, slide presentations) from over 300 events sponsored by the Institute from 2007-2015.
The series "Calendars, Promotional Materials, and Program Brochures" is a collection of printed materials that were displayed, distributed and mailed as invitations, covering the years 2008-2014.
The small series "Photographic Materials" separates out some of the printed photographs and contact sheets from early events (although, users should note that the majority of event photos have been preserved as part of the audiovisual series).
A full set of published yearbooks, the Institute's annually published "Year in Review," offers highlights and overviews of each year's programming.
Finally, this collection's audiovisual series offers not only a detailed inventory of what the collection contains as far as photographed and video-recorded events, but also information about associated program officers and speakers, as well as external links to online published clips and videos for selected events, hosted on the Institute's YouTube channel.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The initial three increments of this collection were transferred to the University Archives in March 2019, with further accretions expected.
Arrangement
RG 24-1 is arranged into four series. 1. Calendars, Promotional Materials, and Program Brochures, 2008-2018. 2. Photographic Materials: Prints and Contact Sheets [ca. 2008-2013]. 3. NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2008-2019. 4. Audiovisual event and program files, 2007-2015. Materials are arranged chronologically in each series by date of event.
Biographical / Historical
New York University, in developing a new "Global Network" of degree granting campuses and academic centers across six continents (NYU New York, NYU Abu Dhabi, and NYU Shanghai), established the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute in 2008, two years prior to the Abu Dhabi campus opening its doors to its first class of students and faculty. The Institute was the first "on-the-ground" operation of the University in the UAE. As a research outreach and sponsorship component, it was established to create and support innovative research programs, organize public discussions with experts from around the world, and invite participation not only from and for the NYU network constituency but also from and for local, regional, and national communities.
The Institute's inaugural program in October 2008, "On the Art of the Novel," featured renowned Lebanese novelist Elias Khoury. Its "first collaboration" came during the November 2008 program "Stephen Hawking's 'A Briefer History of Time'," featuring the Arabic translation of that book by Kalima, the translation initiative launched by Abu Dhabi Authority for Culture and Heritage (ADACH). In December of 2008, "Neurolinguistics and Imaging: Progress and Prospects" was the first multi-day program that the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute sponsored. Early events took place at the Al Mamoura Auditorium in Abu Dhabi.
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute programming was early-on a joint effort between faculty and administration in Abu Dhabi, and faculty and administrative leadership in New York. The Institute created an Advisory Committee that also first convened in Decmeber 2008, and in May of 2009, the NYUAD offices at 19 Washington Square North sponsored the first New York-hosted Institute event, a lecture titled "Building Big: A Critical Examination of the Planning of Mega Urban Transportation." The Institute continues to organize programs in both Abu Dhabi and New York. When the NYU Abu Dhabi downtown campus was built and finally available as a venue for programs, the Institute hosted its first on-campus lecture there in December 2009, "The Predictioneer's Game," a talk about game theory with NYU Professor Bruce Bueno de Mesquita. Student-centered Institute programming was introduced in 2011 with the "Hackathon for Social Good in the Arab World."
Today, the NYUAD Institute continues to sponsor and support multi-day conferences, workshops and seminars relevant to the NYUAD curriculum and areas of research, across a range of subjects from falconry to poetry to genomics to youth unemployment crises. The Institute has become an important asset of the university that seeks to deepen understanding of the world, generate important new knowledge, and facilitate breakthrough discoveries in science and technology.
References and for further information: "10 Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute"
Related Materials
Users and researchers may find additional resources on the NYU Abu Dhabi Institue YouTube Channel.
Research institutes; Universities and Colleges -- institutes; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; NYU Abu Dhabi
- Calendars, Promotional Materials and Program Brochures, 2008-2014
  Scope and Contents
  A collection of printed materials that were displayed, distributed and mailed as invitations, covering the years 2008-2014.
  - Institute Event Calendar/Brochure Prep Notes, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Program Schedule, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Institute Event Calendars, 2008-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Square Institute Event Calendars, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute Event Invitation Announcement Cards, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Institute Event Posters (oversize), Fall 2009 (Map-case 1.C)
  - Institute Event Announcements/Posters, Spring 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Institute Event Program Brochures [incomplete set], 2009-2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program: Embracing Sports in the UAE, November 19-20, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Jointly sponsored by NYUAD Institute, Abu Dhabi Sports Council, and NYU School of Professional Studies, Sports and Society
  - Press Kit, February 2008-February 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographic Materials: Photo prints and Contact Sheets, [ca. 2008 - 2013]
  This is a small series that separates out some of the printed photographs and contact sheets from early events that were transferred with records to the University Archives (users should note that the majority of event photos are digital, and have been preserved as part of the Audiovisual Event Files series).
  - Photographs, January 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Brain Imaging, January 14, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Search for Social Entrepreneurship, January 18, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Education, Media, and Human Development, January 20, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2010 -
  The NYUAD Institute publishes an annual "Year in Review," a yearbook highlighting major events throughout the year. This series includes selected print copies of the publication, as well as E-book versions.
  Note: copies of the NYUAD Institute Year in Review are also in the NYUAD Publications and Ephemera Collection (AD-RG-2), as well as the Records of the Office of Public Affairs: Publications (AD-RG-9).
  - Year In Review, 2010-2011 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Year In Review, 2011-2012 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Year In Review, 2012-2013 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2013-2014 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2014-2015 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2015-2016 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Year In Review, 2017-2018 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Year In Review, 2018-2019 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2018-2019 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Year In Review, 2019-2020 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2020-2021 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Year in Review, 2022-2023 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Anniversary Commemorative Yearbooks/Publications, 2013; 2018
  - Five Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 10 Years: Celebrating 10 Years of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Audiovisual Event Files, 2007-2015
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  NYU Abu Dhabi Institute staff arranged for the photography and video recording of most Institute events. Many of the recordings have been curated and shared on the Institute's YouTube Channel. Records in this series constitute the full packaged files from various lectures, workshops and conferences, and are organized by date of event. Records are primarily audiovisual, and include digital photos, video footage, and in some cases, copies of slide presentations from events 2008 - 2015. Archivists continue to partner with NYUAD Institute staff for the ongoing transfer of inactive materials.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have been minimally processed. The container list below provides a basic inventory of contents. Files are viewable onsite by appointment.
  - Program DVDs
    - On the Art of the Novel, Oct. 7, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Elias Khoury
    - NYUAD Institute Event Photos, Fall 2008 (Box 4)
    - SIPEX - Sea Ice Physics & Ecology Experiment, Oct. 17, 2007 (Box 4)
    - Banking the World, Nov 10, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Speaker/Officiator: Jonathan Morduch
    - Stephen Hawking's A Briefer History of Time [2 copies], Nov. 12, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Glennys Farrar
    - America's Elections 2008 [2 copies], Nov. 16, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hassan Fattah; Bob Shrum; Rogan Kersh
    - Outside the Box Alternate Modernities, Nov 18, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Edward J. Sullivan
    - Kluge: the Haphazard Construction of the Human Mind, Dec. 15, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Gary Marcus
    - Edward Said's The World, The Text, and the Critic: A Discussion on Edward Said, A Conversation with Marina Warner (video), Dec. 17, 2008 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Warner
    - Edward Said's The World, The Text, and the Critic: A Discussion on Edward Said, A Conversation with Marina Warner (Photos), Dec. 17, 2008 (Box 4)
    - Brain Imaging (Video), Jan. 14, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Heeger
    - Brain Imaging (Photos), Jan. 14, 2009 (Box 4)
    - The Search for Social Entrepreneurship (Photos), [2 copies], Jan. 18, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paul C. Light
    - NYU Conference on Education, Media (Photos), Jan. 22, 2009 (Box 4)
      Alternate DVD title: NYU Abu Dhabi Steinhardt Emirates Palace Hotel (Photos)
    - In the Public Eye: Media and Civil Society in the Arab World (Photos), Jan. 22, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hussein Amin; Nabil Khatib; Rami Khouri; Martin Newland; Lawrence Pintak; Zayani Mohamed
    - In the Public Eye: Media and Civil Society in the Arab World (Video), Jan. 22, 2009 (Box 4)
    - Eisenstein's Film Forum, Feb. 12, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mikhail Iampolski; Richard Allen
    - The Two Europes (Photos), Apr. 15, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Levering Lewis
    - On Arabian Oral Poetry and Tribal Lore, Apr. 26, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Saad Abdalla Sowayan; Bernard Haykel; Philip F. Kennedy
    - Climate Change: Financing Green Development, May 4, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Richard Stewart; Bernard Haykel
    - Climate Change: Financing Green Development (Photos) [3 discs], May 3-5, 2009 (Box 4)
      Includes photos of NYU Dinners in Abu Dhabi at Intercontinental Hotel, Royal Meridien, Hiltonia
    - Islamic Art and Architecture: Christian Images in Islamic Art, Sep. 29, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yasser Tabbaa
    - Le Corbusier's Toward an Architecture, in Conjuction with Kalima, Oct. 1, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jean-Louis Cohen
    - Completing the Circuit: Formula 1, Yas Island, Oct. 15, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Khaldoon Al Mubarak; Falah Al Ahbabi; Richard Cregan; Victor Matheson
    - Cosmpolitanism, Multiculturalism, Oct. 21, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cyrus R.K. Patell
    - The Conservation of Islamic Heritage and Architecture in Cairo and the UAE, Nov. 11, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Peter Sheehan; Nicholas Warner
    - CO2 Rising: The World's Greatest Challenge, Nov. 15, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tyler Volk; Anne Rademacher
    - Mapping the Ancient World, Nov. 22, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Rita Wright
    - Teaching the Ancient World, Nov. 23, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Andrew Monson; Walter Scheidel
    - Higher Education in the Global Age (Sunday, Part 1), Dec. 6, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Al Bloom; Mariët Westermann
    - Higher Education in the Global Age (Sunday, Part 2), Dec. 6, 2009 (Box 4)
    - Higher Education in the Global Age (Monday, Part 1), Dec. 7, 2009 (Box 4)
    - Higher Education in the Global Age (Monday, Part 2), Dec. 7, 2009 (Box 4)
    - The Predictioneer's Game, Dec. 9, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Bruce Bueno de Mesquita
    - The Arabian Nights, Dec. 9, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Warner; Karl Sabbagh
    - Writers in Conversation with Arabian Nights, Dec. 15, 2009 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Philip Kennedy; Marina Warner
    - The Arabian Nights, Dec. 16, 2009 (Box 4)
    - The Arabian Nights, Dec. 17, 2009 (Box 4)
    - The Arabian Nights (Resize), Dec. 15-17, 2009 (Box 4)
    - The Eighth Day of Creation [2 copies], Jan. 6, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David A. Scicchitano; Gloria Coruzzi
    - Genomics and Systems Biology, Jan. 6, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David A. Scicchitano; Gloria Coruzzi; etc
    - Genomics and Systems Biology Day 1 Sessions 1-4, Jan. 6, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Genomics and Systems Biology Day 2 Sessions 1-4, Jan. 7, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Future Horizons of Fundamental Physics, Jan. 11-14, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mariët Westermann; David Spergel
    - Hubble Trouble: The Expanding Universe and Dark Energy Enigma, Jan. 14, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Georgi Dvali
    - Matters of Taste [3 copies], Jan. 17, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Charles Spence; Barry C. Smith
    - Strategic Issues Facing the Port of New York and Dubai, Jan. 24, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Asaf Ashar
    - Islamic Art in the Gulf Region [2 copies], Jan. 28, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jochen Sokoly
    - Emirates Center for Strategic Studies and Research (Name and Logo), Feb. 01, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Emerging Powers, Global Security, Feb. 8-10, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Dr. Stephen Krasner; Strobe Talbott
    - Power and Responsibility [2 copies], Feb. 9, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Bruce D. Jones; Talbott Strobe
    - Abu Dhabi as a Leadership City, Feb. 09, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Texts and Textiles, Feb. 18, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Islamic Art and Architecture, Feb. 18-21, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Visual Reflections on Arabic Poetry, Feb 21, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Africa and the Indian Ocean, Mar. 14-16, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yaw Nyarko, Bernard Haykel
    - The Magic of Words, Mar. 28, 2010 (Box 4)
    - A Life's Journey, Mar. 30, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers:Parvis Tanavoli
    - The Collection and Display of Islamic Art [3 copies], Mar. 31, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Priscilla Soucek; Haidar Navina
    - Library of Arabic Liturature, Apr. 6, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Memorandum Signing, April 6, 2010 (Box 4)
    - A Tale of Two Cities and of Climate Change, Apr. 11, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Holland
    - Beyond Child Indicators, Apr. 13, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hirokazu Yoshikawa, Pia Britto
    - Art Museums Here and Now, Apr. 18, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Zaki Nusseibeh, Hilary Ballon
    - Museums Tomorrow, Apr. 18, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Neil MacGregor; Kavita Singh; John Onians
    - Forces Moulding Mega Urban Transportation Projects, Apr. 20, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Harry T. Dimitriou
    - A Brief History of Arab Music, May. 5, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mustafa Said
    - The Relevance and Irrelevance of Muslim Political Traditions, May 9, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Aziz Al-Azmeh
    - From the World Wide Web, May 11, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Keith Ross
    - Global Finance, Sept. 16, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Global Finance After the Crisis, Sept. 16, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ingo Walter
    - From Metaphor to Model, Sept. 26, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mary Poovey
    - Interdisciplinary Studies in Information Tech, Oct. 3-4, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Anindya Ghose, Marcus K. Rogers.
    - Understanding Privacy in Context, Oct. 4, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Helen Nissenbaum; Mireille Hildebrandt
    - The Future is Now [2 copies], Oct. 10, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Zurkow
    - The Ethical Brain, Oct. 20, 2010 (Box 4)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Micheal Gazzaniga
    - Global Cost-Benefit Analysis, Oct. 26, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Michael A. Livermore; Richard L. Revesz.
    - The Use of Economics on Environmental Policy, Oct. 27, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Richard L. Revesz; Oliver Harrison
    - Interpreting the 1001 Nights for the Stage, Oct. 27, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Philip Kennedy, Tim Supple
    - The Cosmopolitans, Oct. 31-Nov. 7, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Zubin Shroff, Joanne Savio
    - Interpreting the 1001 Nights for the Stage (Performance), Nov. 4, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tim Supple, Stage Director
    - Situating Sustainability, Nov. 8, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mary Candenasso, Greg Beckett.
    - Realizing the Ecological City, Nov. 08, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mary Candenasso; Julie Sze
    - Leadership for a New Era: Fostering Leadership for Public Well-Being, Nov. 16, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Fadi Ghandour; Barbara Ibrahim; Asya Al-Lamki
    - In Defense of Politics, Nov. 21, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Steven Smith
    - The Ten Great Ideas of Science, Nov. 24, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Peter Atkins; Joel Bernstein
    - Galileo's Feifer Book Discussion, Nov. 24, 2010 (Box 5)
    - Nationalization of the Workforce in the GCC, Nov. 27, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: May Al-Dabbagh; Jasim Ahmed Mohamed Al-Ali.
    - US-Iran Is Diplomacy Possible, Dec. 8, 2010 (Box 5)
    - Obama's Foreign Policy, Dec. 12, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Traub; Hassan Fattah
    - Emerging Challenges and Opportunities in the Gulf [2 copies], Dec. 15, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: William Rugh
    - US, Iran and the Gulf: Regional Context and Transnational Currents, Dec. 15, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Farhad Kazemi, Ali Banuazizi, Augustus Richard Norton
    - US, Iran, and the Gulf, Dec. 15-16, 2010 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Leila Fawaz; Nelida Fuccaro
    - Understanding Social Entrepreneurship, Jan. 6, 2011 (Box 5)
    - Supercomputing the Imperative and the Path Forward, Jan. 9, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Frank Baetke; Antonio Navarra
    - The Data and Computer-Driven Transformation, Jan. 9, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Harry Edward Seidel
    - The Evolution of Death, Jan. 12, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tyler Volk
    - Probability Theory, Statistical Physics, Jan. 16, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jean-Philippe Bouchaud; Katepalli Sreenivasan
    - The (Unfortunate) Complexity of Economic Systems, Jan. 16, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jean-Philippe Bouchaud
    - Non-Polygonal Image Shapes, Jan. 17, 2011 (Box 5)
    - Climate Change and the Mathematics of Sea Ice, Jan. 19, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Kenneth M. Golden
    - Collaborative Workshop on Climate Finance, Jan. 22, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Robert Bradley, Richard Stewart
    - Climate Finance [2 copies], Jan. 22-23, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Dr. Jaber Eidha Al Jaberi; Richard Stewart
    - Garden's of Eden in the Human Imagination, Jan. 23, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mariët Westermann
    - Arab Voices, What they are Saying to Us, and Why it Matters, Jan. 24, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Zogby
    - Middle Eastern Comics and their Place in the 21st Century, Jan. 25, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Qais Sedki; Charles Kochman
    - Trends in Air Transportation, Implications for Abu Dhabi and New York, Jan. 30, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: R. John Hansman
    - The Life and Afterlife of Indian Images, Feb. 7, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sanchita Balachandran
    - The Life and Afterlife of Indian Images by Sanchita Balachandran, Feb. 7, 2011 (Box 5)
    - The Interface Between Field Archaeology and Conservation, Feb. 7-9, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sanchita Balachandran; Hossam Mahdy
    - Current Political Events in Egypt and Middle East, Feb. 10, 2011 (Box 5)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tarik Yousef; Shadi Hamid; Nasr Arif; Hassan Riaz
    - Egypt Discussion: Al Mamoura, Feb. 10, 2011 (Box 5)